Finding Aid for the Anthony C. Beilenson Papers LSC.0391
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Santa Monica Bay
  - OCS--General Information (1) (Box 69, Folder 5)
    Map Pacific Region Offshore Continental Shelf (OCS); Interior Dept Pacific Summary clippings 4 Issues; correspondence re Union Oil Drilling in Santa Barbara Channel Islands Marine Sanctuary; Governor Deukmejian Letter to Interior Opposing Lease Moratorium; Congressional Research Service Background material on Offshore Oil & Gas Exploration & OCS Land Leasing; Congressman Panetta Letter to Colleagues
  - OCS--General Information (2) (Box 70, Folder 1)
    Newspaper clippings & reprints; Beilenson Statement before House Subcommittee on Interior; Letter to Secretary Watt; Beilenson news release re Oil Lease Prohibition; Beilenson Statement before Bureau of Land Management; Mayor Bradley Letter to Governor Brown; California; Congressional Delegation Letter to President Carter; clippings by Comptroller General of U.S. re Interior's New Offshore Leasing Program
  - OCS--General Information (3) (Box 70, Folder 2)
    Governor Brown Testimony on Gas & Oil Leasing; Interior Dept News Release re Update Estimates on Reserves; Exxon Letter re Beilenson Visit to Santa Barbara Channel Platform; Congressional Research Service Clippings: Oil Pollution Liability Statutes; "Cook with Offshore Oil;" Directory to Federal, State, & Local OCS (Offshore Continental Shelf)-Related Activities & Contacts
  - Channel Islands Marine Sanctuary (Box 70, Folder 3)
    Newspaper clippings & reprints; correspondence of Defenders of Wildlife; Santa Barbara County; Contact Sheet for Channel Island Supporters; Status of Marine Sanctuary Program; Congressional Research Services re Suspension of Regulations re Channel Islands & Poi; Reyes Farallon National Marine Sanctuaries; Attachment to Final Environmental Impact Statement re proposed Channel Islands Sanctuary
    Assembly Bill: 2975 to Establish Channel Islands Marine National Park
  - Sewage Sludge Waste (Box 70, Folder 4)
    Hyperion Water Pollution Control Plant Ocean Discharges Permit; correspondence & Comptroller General clippings re Waivers for Coastal Wastewater Treatment Plants; proposed Sludge Management Program for L.A. & Orange County; Comptroller General Clippings: Using Solid Waste; Conserve Resources & to Create Energy; proposed Sludge Farm in Las Virgenes Valley; Tapia Wastewater Treatment Facility
- Santa Monica Mountains
  - SMMNRA--Whizzin Acquisition (1) (Box 37, Folder 3)
    Newsletters, correspondence, Misc. information re Santa Monica Mountain National Recreational Area (SMMNRA) Whizzin Acquisition, major Fax transmittals include 159 Homes to be Built on Whizzin Property, Sierra Club and Las Virgenes Homeowners Federation Inc. v. County of Los Angeles; Paramount Ranch Project, Mira Development Corporation et al., Plaintiffs and Appellants, v. City of San Diego et al.
  - SMMNRA--Whizzin Acquisition (2) (Box 37, Folder 4)
    Notes, correspondence, Misc. information re Santa Monica Mountain National Recreational Area (SMMNRA) Whizzin Acquisition, major Fax transmittals include Zone Change Case No. 86-010-(5), Testimony of Congressman Beilenson before The Los Angeles County Board of Supervisors
  - SMMNRA--Whizzin Acquisition (3) (Box 37, Folder 5)
    Notes, correspondence, Misc. information re Santa Monica Mountain National Recreational Area (SMMNRA) Whizzin Acquisition, major Fax transmittals include Zone Change Case, Testimony of Congressman Beilenson before The Los Angeles County Board of Supervisors
  - SMMNRA--Whizzin Acquisition (4) (Box 37, Folder 6)
    Notes, correspondence, Misc. information re Santa Monica Mountain National Recreational Area (SMMNRA) Whizzin Acquisition, including minutes, correspondence from Board of Supervisors of County of Los Angeles, correspondence from Historic Oaks Foundation, Las Virgenes Homeowners Federation; correspondence re Zone Change Case, Addendum to The Land Protection Plan
  - Santa Monica Mountains Land Exchange (Box 81, Folder 4)
    Includes Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area California Proposed Land Exchange Environmental Impact Statement Transcript of Public Hearing; Draft Environmental Impact Statement National Park Service proposed Land Exchange Cheeseboro Canyon, Palo Comado Canyon Santa Monica Mountains; Newspaper Reprint; Beilenson Letter to Superintendent, Santa Monica Mountains NRA
  - Santa Monica Mountains Land Exchange EIS (Box 82, Folder 1)
    Contains Final Environmental Impact Statement National Park Service Proposed Land Exchange Cheeseboro Canyon Palo Comado Canyon Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area
  - Cheeseboro Canyon report July, 1990 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    Two photographs of Canyon; Clippings: The Cheeseboro Canyon Landswap Controversy An Analysis prepared by Save Open Space July, 1990; sections include: Congressional Involvement; National Park Service Involvement; & Conservancy Involvement
  - For Steve Smith Mountain Park (Box 82, Folder 3)
    Folder containing Political Documents re Save The Mountain Park Coalition & Santa Monica Mountains Conservancy; sections include: Lobbying packet '89, Hearing, news release, Beilenson Letter; Folder: Agreement between Bob Hope & The Santa Monica; Mountains Conservancy
  - Management & Protection Plans (Box 82, Folder 4)
    Contains General Protection Plan Santa Monica Mountains 1982; Land Protection Plan Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area 1984; Addendum to The Land Protection Plan for Santa Monica Mountains 1987
  - Development & Zuma Trancas (Box 82, Folder 5)
    Contains Development Monitoring Santa Monica Mountains NRA Planning Beyond Park Boundaries 1991; Zuma-Trancas Canyons Draft Development Concept Plan Environmental Assessment September 1992
  - Santa Monica Mountains--Reseda Exten. Mulholland Scenic Parkway (1) (Box 83, Folder 1)
    Newspaper clippings & reprints; Homeowners of Encino, Councilman Marvin Braude for AB 1152; copy of Bill; Santa Monica Mountains Conservancy agendas; Mulholland Gateway Park Draft Master Plan; Beilenson Letter to Braude; Beilenson Letter to Daily News; Draft of Beilenson Letter to Mayor Bradley; clippings of The Citizens' Advisory Committee on The Mulholland Scenic Parkway; Friends of Caballero Canyon
    Senate Bill: AB 1152 Allow California Parks Dept to Condition A Tract Map with A Road Through Topanga State Park, Avoiding Widening Reseda Boulevard
  - Santa Monica Mountains--Reseda Exten. Mulholland Scenic Parkway (Box 83, Folder 2)
    Newspaper clippings & reprints; Discussion with Rosalind Waymann of Councilman Braude's Office re Mulholland; Testimony before L.A. City Council; maps of Reseda Extension & Caballero Canyon; correspondence re EIR for Mulholland Crest Park; Sierra Club; Friends; Caballero Canyon; Pacific Palisades Residents Association; Traffic Study; Topanga Petition; Temescal Canyon; Harlan Lee Development
  - Santa Monica Mountains: Mulholland Gateway Park (Box 83, Folder 3)
    Newspaper clippings & reprints; announcement of meeting on Mulholland Gateway Park Draft Plan; Key Elements of Plan; Map; announcement of Site Tour of Park
  - Santa Monica Mountains--Hardship Acquisition (Box 83, Folder 4)
    Newspaper reprints; National Park Service Letter to Landowner Claiming Hardship; correspondence Within Service re Funding for Hardship Cases in Priority Acquisition Areas; Guidelines for Cases in Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area; correspondence to & from National Park Service re Landowners requests to be Considered Hardship Situation
  - Santa Monica Mountains--Reports, Studies, etc. (1) (Box 84, Folder 3)
    Contains National Urban Recreation Study Executive Report; Santa Monica Mountains Study; Land Use Profile of The City of L.A. Statistical Area Basis; Congressional Research Service: Recreation & The Coastal Zone, & Review of The Acquisition Costs of National Seashores; Outdoor Recreation: Resources & Politics; Needed for California:Great Seashore & Mountain Park; Sunset Smithsonian
  - Santa Monica Mountains--Reports, Studies, etc. (2) (Box 84, Folder 4)
    Contains National Urban Recreation Study Los Angeles Long Beach Anaheim; Why The National Park Service's Appropriation request Process Makes Congressional Oversight Difficult; Federal Drive to Acquire Private Lands Should be Reassessed; Federal Land, Acquisitions by Condemnation--Opportunities to Reduce Delays & Costs
  - Santa Monica Mountains--Reports, Studies, etc. (3) (Box 85, Folder 1)
    L.A. Time Home Magazine; National Parks & Conservation Magazine; Beilenson newsletter Drafts; Cry California; "Playground-Building Battleground;" "Preliminary Urban Parks Study;" Exploring The Santa Monica Mountains; Prehistoric Indian Rock Art: Fax transmittals & Concerns; "Park Barrel Bill;" "U.S. Park? Things Are Looking Up" from L.A. Times
  - Santa Monica Mountains--NPS Development Plans for Specific Sites (Box 85, Folder 2)
    National Parks & Conservation Magazine; Development Concept Plan Rancho Sierra Vista Satwiwa Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area 1984; Environmental Assessment 1983; Summary of Planning Proposals; correspondence re Paramount Ranch, & Summary of Planning Proposals; Paramount Ranch Environmental Assessment Development Concept Plan 1982; Finding of No Significant Impact 1983
  - Santa Monica Mountains--NPS--Important Information (Box 85, Folder 3)
    12 Point Plan National Park Service; City of Agoura request for Park Headquarters; Walks on The Wild Side; Mountains Restoration Trust; Hunting; Kuehn to become Santa Monica Superintendent; Estimated Visitation; Legislative Cost Estimate; Major Equestrian & Hiking Trails; Air Quality; Possible Use During Olympic Games; Santa Monica Mountains Gifts Catalog
  - Santa Monica Mountains--PR Type Information--NPS (1) (Box 85, Folder 4)
    National Park Service news releases re Santa Monica Schedule, Raptors, Paramount Ranch, Fire Suppression, transportation, Geology, Anthropology, Will Rogers State Historic Park, Wildflowers, Evening Programs, Outdoor Jobs, Recreation Workshops; William O. Doug Outdoor Classroom; Grand Canyon Folder; Santa Monica Mountains Map; Trust for Public Land 1983 Annual Clippings; Planning Issues; Background information
  - Santa Monica Mountains--PR Type Information--NPS (2) (Box 85, Folder 5)
    Sulphur Dioxide & Ozone Study; pamphlet introducing the park; flier re seminars offered at park; Tree People; Comments on GAO Audit of Approved Land Protection Plans; National Park pamphlets: Channel Islands, Cabrillo, Sequoia Kings Canyon, Yosemite; Golden Gate, Redwood, Joshua Tree, National Park System in California
  - S.M. Mts.--Tour (Box 86, Folder 1)
    Handwritten notes; possible use of Marine Helicopter; request for Helicopter for use by House Subcommittee considering Beilenson Legislation re Santa Monica Mountains; Proposed Itinerary; Thank You to Santa Monica Bus Lines for providing transportation
    Assembly Bill: Correspondence re HR 7264 to Establish The Channel Islands & The Santa Monica Mountains National Park & Seashore
  - Charlie Warren's Trip 7/17 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    Handwritten notes re Tour of Santa Monica Mountains by Charlie Warren & Helicopter Arrangements
  - Social Accommodations (Box 86, Folder 3)
    Draft Memo re Informal Cocktail Party; Thank You notes to Palisades Couple for Hosting National Parks Congressional Subcommittee Reception & to Holiday Inn for Accommodations
  - Deer Canyon Testimony 4/12 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    California Coastal Commission news release re Public Hearings re clippings evaluating Offshore Liquified Natural Gas (LNG) Terminal Sites; summary of major points at meeting; Staff Recommendation on & final clippings Evaluating & Ranking LNG Terminal Sites; Commission Act; Ranking Sites; background information; Sierra Club Statement re Ranking; Beilenson Statement on proposed Natural Gas in Deer Canyon
  - Conservation Mailing List (Box 86, Folder 5)
    Labels containing 28 Names & Addresses of Conservation Organizations
  - City Council Testimony (Box 86, Folder 6)
    Statement to Senate Committee Energy & Natural Resources, Subcomm Parks, re S 975 Williams Bingham Bill to improve public access to parks; typed & handwritten notes; statement by Linda Levie Friedman, Legislative Assistant to Anthony C. Beilenson re HR 7264 to Establish The Santa Monica Mountains & Channel Islands National Park & Seashore
    House Bill: S 975 Williams Bingham Bill to improve public access to parks
    Assembly Bill: HR 7264 to establish The Santa Monica Mountains & Channel Islands National Park & Seashore
  - NPS Tour & 1/11 Meeting (Box 86, Folder 7)
    List of Names & Telephone Numbers for Ventura County Recreation & Parks Dept; telephone notes; agenda for National Park Service (NPS) Tour; list of people attending meeting; tour itinerary; rough draft & copies of Thank You letters re tour
  - HR 7264 Local Support (1) (Box 86, Folder 8)
    List of Co-Sponsors of HR 7264 to Establish Channel Islands & Santa Monica Mountains National Park & Seashore; Members of Senate Energy & Natural Resources Commission; Constituent Letter to Congressman Goldwater re Wildlife in Santa Monicas; Interior Dept N; Release; North Benedict Canyon proposed Paleontological Park; copies of Color Photos; Santa Monica Mountains Plan Briefing Agency & Phone Numbers
    Assembly Bill: HR 7264 to Establish Channel Islands & Santa Monica Mountains National Park & Seashore
  - HR 7264 Local Support (2) (Box 86, Folder 9)
    Sierra Club Activities re Beilenson Legislation; Checklist for Reception; HR 380 Congressman Goldwater to Establish Santa Monica Urban Park; Telephone notes; South Coast Regional Commission Membership List; NPS Acquisition Policies & Relocation Assistance; Progress, Property & Just Compensation The Power of Eminent Domain Pamphlets
    Assembly Bill: HR 7264 to Establish Channel Islands & Santa Monica Mountains National Park & Seashore; HR 380 to Establish Santa Monica Urban Park
  - The Hearings (1) (Box 86, Folder 10)
    List of Possible Places for September 1, 1977 Congressional Hearings in Santa Monica; correspondence re Concerned Citizens for Property Rights Opposing Beilenson House Bill 7264; Statement by Huey Johnson, Secretary for Resources, Santa Monica Mountains; South Coast; Regional Commission Supports; notes re Hearings; Las Virgenes Municipal Water District; telephone notes; Witness List; List Equipment Needed
  - The Hearings (2) (Box 86, Folder 11)
    Subcommittee on National Parks & Insular Affairs Hearings in Santa Monica re HR 7264 & Identical Bills HR 8781 & 8782, and HR 380, with list of witnesses; Councilman Ferraro Support; Congressman Burton news release re Hearing; Beilenson Letter request; Support; copy of HR 7264 & Section Analysis; notes re Slide Presentation; Information for Witnesses; Beilenson Thank You letters
    Assembly Bill: HR 7264, 8781, 8782 to Establish Channel Islands & Santa Monica Mountains National Park & Seashore; HR 380 for Santa Monica Urban Park
  - Santa Monica Mountains Planning reports (Box 86, Folder 12)
    Contains Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area Recreation Transportation System Element Final report, Executive Summary, & Appendices
  - Land Protection Visitor Services (Box 87, Folder 1)
    Contains Land Protection Plan Santa Monica Mountains 1984; Visitor Services Project Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area 1993
  - National Parks & Rec Act 1978 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    Contains Legislative History of The National Parks & Recreation Act of 1978 (Public Law 95-625)
  - S.M. Mts. and Channel Islands S.M. Mts. Comprehensive Planning Commission(1) (Box 87, Folder 3)
    Correspondence from Santa Monica Mountains Comprehensive Planning Commission Congratulating Beilenson on Field Trip & Hearings; Pending Developments; Maps; Preliminary Plan Land Use Elements; Coastal Commission Liaison Commission agenda; Citizens Advisory Commission agenda; Newspaper reprints; Compatibility of Land Uses & Constraints; Land Capability Matrix; Economic Element Task Force; Staff Sketch Plan
  - S.M. Mts. and Channel Islands S.M. Mts. Comprehensive Planning Commission (2) (Box 87, Folder 4)
    Santa Monica Mountains Comprehensive Planning Commission meeting agenda & minutes; Overall Planning Objectives; Composite Land Use Plan of Local Governments Within The Santa Monica Mountains Zone; Development Fax transmittals Commission; Additions to Workplan; Citizens Advisory Commission; Impending Development & Land Division Fax transmittals Commission meeting agenda & minutes; clippings on Mulholland Scenic Parkway; Alternate Sketch Plans & Hearings
  - S.M. Mts. and Channel Islands S.M. Mts. Comprehensive Planning Commission (3) (Box 87, Folder 5)
    Santa Monica Mountains Comprehensive Planning Commission meeting agendas & minutes; memos re Mobile Homes, Mudd Ranch, Regional Issues; Overall Planning Objectives; Land Use Element, maps; Letter to Beilenson re Commission Progress; Statistical Clippings on Park Acquisition in The Santa Monica Mountains 1978; Conservation Element; Coastal Commission Liaison Commission; Newspaper reprints; Assembly Joint Resolution 65
    Senate Bill: Joint Resolution 65 Memorializing Congress to Pass Legislation Creating Santa Monica Mountains National Park
  - S.M. Mts. and Channel Islands S.M. Mts. Comprehensive Planning Commission (4) (Box 88, Folder 1)
    Santa Monica Mountains Citizens Advisory Committee Workshop on Mountain Ordinance Fax transmittals Schedule; announcement of Other Workshops; correspondence re AB 2377 Extending Life of Santa Monica Mountains Planning Commission; AB 3663 to Fund Phase I of Park Acquisition; Commission meeting agendas; minutes; Economic Element; Pending Acquisitions; Public Hearing notices; Fire related Policies; Trails Element
    Senate Bill: AB 2377; AB 3663
  - Santa Monica Mountains District Plans (Box 88, Folder 2)
    Includes Newspaper reprints; Mulholland Corridor Field Trip Guide; City of L.A. Department of City Planning Beverly Crest Bel Air District Plan & Map, & Brentwood Pacific Palisades District proposed Plan;Hollywood Community Plan; Sherman Oaks Studio; Toluca Lake District Plan; correspondence re Use of Slope Criteria in Community Plan Map & Text (Santa Monica Mountain Area)
  - Environmental Studies (Box 88, Folder 3)
    Includes Final Environmental Impact Statement for Ready Missile Test Facility; Final report to Legislature Ventura Los Angeles Mountain & Coastal Study Commission; State Open Space & Resource Conservation Program for California
  - Materials re H.R. 12536 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    Text of H.R. 12536, The National Parks & Recreation Act of 1978; Summary of Santa Monica Mountains Section of Act; Full Text of Section; Section re Act in Congressional Record
  - Telephone Calls--S.M.Mts. (Box 88, Folder 5)
    Constituent Legislative Inquiry or request Form; Handwritten Messages on Note Paper re Santa Monica Mountains
  - Land Acquisition (Box 88, Folder 6)
    Pamphlets: NPS Acquisition Policies & Relocation Assistance; How & Why The Federal Government Acquires Property for Public Purposes; Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions; Uniform Relocation Assistance & Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970; Land Acquisition Practice & Procedures agenda & roster of Participants
  - Requests--Santa Monica Mts. (Box 88, Folder 7)
    Includes Constituent Legislative Inquiry or request Forms re Santa Monica Mountains; Letter from Aide Accompanying Information; Thank You from Recipient of materials; Letter requesting Internship
  - HR 12536 Misc. (1) (Box 88, Folder 8)
    Includes Charter Golden Gate National Recreation Area Advisory Commission; Beilenson Draft Letter re Santa Monica Mountains; Fire Problem; Committee to Re-Elect Congressman Beilenson Letter; History of Yellowstone; Park Map; Conejo Valley Attitude, Federal Register re 1978 Park Act; Federation of Hillside & Canyon Associations meeting agenda & minutes; People for The Preservation of Agoura
    Assembly Bill: HR 12536
  - HR 12536 Misc. (2) (Box 89, Folder 1)
    Correspondence re Cornell Road Realignment from Santa Monica Mountains Trail Council; Wilsonia report No. 2; Federation of Hillside & Canyon Associations meeting agenda& minutes; Senate Commission Hearing; Topanga Canyon; Potential Acquisition; Wonderland Preservation Association; copy HR 12536; Comparison of Dept of Interior Bill for Santa Monica Mountains & Omnibus Parks Bill
  - S.M. Mts. and Channel Islands background information (Box 89, Folder 2)
    Includes maps; Sierra Club correspondence re Fire; Postcards; Passage of 1978 Parks Act Through Commission; Congressional Record; Flood Damage; Memo re Inclusion of Ocean Water areas in Park; Acreage Breakdown; Santa Rosa Island; Environmental Assessment; Beilenson; Statement re Park; Mulholland Scenic Corridor; Great Seashore & Mountain Park; Green Line Parks; Urban Parks; Breathing Space
    Assembly Bill: HR 12095 certain Area of Santa Monicas Under Greenline Park & Preserve; HR 6625 Pine Barrens National Ecological Reserve in New Jersey
    Senate Bill: AB 163 Santa Monica Mountains Comprehensive Planning Act of 1975
  - HR 12536--Background (Box 89, Folder 3)
    Amendment to HR 12536; Accompanying House clippings Providing for Increases in Appropriations Ceilings; House clippings Accompanying HR 12234 Amending The Land & Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965; KHJ-TV Editorial "Conflicts of Interest;" Arguments against A Hi Level of Defense Spending; notes by Staff; copy of H.R. 7264 to Establish Channel Islands & Santa Monica Mountains National Park
  - HR 12536--Summary & Report (Box 89, Folder 4)
    Contains Reprint copies of clippings Accompanying HR 12536 Providing for Increases in Appropriations Ceilings, Development Ceilings, Land Acquisition & Boundary Changes in certain Federal Park & Recreation areas & for Other Purposes 1978
  - SMMCPC (Box 89, Folder 5)
    Santa Monica Mountains Comprehensive Planning Commission (SMMCPC) Letter to Congressman Dornan re Roberts Ranch; Complete Text of Preliminary Santa Monica Mountains Comprehensive Plan, including Map
  - Delaporte Tour NPS Map Trip (Box 89, Folder 6)
    Handwritten notes re National Park Service (NPS) Tour, including Possibility of A Helicopter; Sierra Club meeting
  - Channel Islands (Box 89, Folder 7)
    Correspondence re Marine Environment; Santa Barbara Island Ecological Reserve; Anacapa Island Trail Booklet; flyer; newspaper clippings; California Law re State Marine Sanctuaries; Memo re Inclusion of Ocean Water areas in National Park & Seashore; Public Hearing re National Monument; Folders re Timeline, Map, brochure, & Background for Islands Workshop; Letter from Botanical Expert re Islands
  - S.M. Mts. and Channel Islands Meetings--memos & Misc. (Box 90, Folder 1)
    Federally Funded Bus Service in Santa Monica Mountains; Implementation Symposium; Letter from Assemblyman Berman re AB 3663; Complaint re Alternate Bill; List of Park Supporters; copy of S 2876; Mayor Bradley Office Meeting; Concerned Landowners; Mulholland; Scenic Corridor; Sierra Club; Land Acquisition; Sewage; Topanga Fire; copy of S 2306; Nike Missiles; Beilenson Statement before Senate Commission
    House Bill: S 2306 to Establish System of Reserves to Protect Scenic Sites; S 2876 to Provide Increases in Appropriations for Park System
    Senate Bill: AB 3663 Providing for Santa Monica Park Land Acquisitions
  - Santa Monica Mountains--Land Acquisition. Individual Hardship Cases (Box 90, Folder 2)
    Newspaper Clippings; telephone messages; letters to & from Beilenson re Assistance
  - Santa Monica Mountains: LACTC Proposal re Cross Mountain Road (Box 90, Folder 3)